A Guide to the Conrad W. Anner papers FA045
Rockefeller Archive Center
Conrad W. Anner papers
1912-1945
Rockefeller Archive Center
Anner, Conrad W. (1889-1960)
Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.)
Rockefeller Foundation
China Medical Board (U.S.)
Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board
Peking Union Medical College
FA045
0.95 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes, and 1 half letter-size document box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
An architect, Conrad W. Anner was born in Berlin, Germany, on December 20, 1889, the son of Edmund C. Anner. Conrad Anner graduated from the Division of Architecture of the Gewerbe Akademie, Chemnitz, Saxony, in 1909 and emigrated to the United States the same year. He married Caroline H. Foster in 1915; they had two children.
Anner was first employed as a draughtsman by the Boston architectural firm Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge (1910-1917) and then by the Boston architect Thomas M. James (1917-1919). In 1919 he was hired by The Rockefeller Foundation as architectural draughtsman during the construction of Peking Union Medical College. Anner remained at PUMC until 1930 as supervisor of architectural work.
Before returning to the United States, he was employed by St. Luke's International Hospital (Tokyo, Japan) to revise the plans of the hospital, and by the Chinese Government to design the National Institute for Physical Research in Shanghai and the National Meteorological Institute in Nanking.
Following his return to the United States in 1931, Anner worked for the architectural firm Perry, Shaw & Hepburn as Superintendent of Construction at Colonial Williamsburg.
Conrad W. Anner died in 1960.
Scope and Contents
The Conrad W. Anner papers include correspondence and reports relating to his employment by the China Medical Board of The Rockefeller Foundation and the China Medical Board of New York, Inc., during which time he worked on construction projects at Peking Union Medical College. A few items relate to his work at Colonial Williamsburg.
Of special note in this collection are a report in Chinese, with a partial translation, on the building specifications from the City of Peking to the Committee of Construction for the Peking National Library, and two reports and two news releases relating to Colonial Williamsburg. There are no personal papers.
Related Materials
See also the Rockefeller Foundation Archives, Record Group 4 (China Medical Board), and the China Medical Board of New York, Inc. records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers of Conrad W. Anner were donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center by Francis Anner via multiple records ingests between 1977 and 1985.
Arrangement
As received.
- Correspondence, 1912-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reports - Peking Union Medical College, 1912-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  "Programme of the Medical Conference, Peking Union Medical College, September 15-22, 1921."
- Print Made from an Antique Wood Cut Found in the Yellow Temple, Peking, China, 1912-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
- Reports - Colonial Williamsburg, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  "Charity in Colonial Virginia," H. R. Shurtleff, 1933
- Conrad W. Anner photographs, 1050; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Photographs
  - Peking the Beautiful (Box A)
  - Thailand (Box 38, Folder 378)
  - China 1 (Box 38, Folder 379)
  - China (Box 38, Folder 380)
  - China (Box 38, Folder 381)
  - China (Box 39, Folder 382)
  - Peking Union Medical College (Box 39, Folder 383)
  - C. W. Anner Lantern Slides - China (Box 2)
  - C. W. Anner Lantern Slides - China (Box 3)
  - C. W. Anner - China